on the previous episode of ignoring the
back of the mansion okay come on
oh no guys i think i've lost all my
items oh
no
i'm just gonna listen to some music and
think about what i've done
wait a minute
i'm rich
i have enough diamonds to just buy all
my stuff back yeah i think i can i can
handle this i do actually have enough
netherite ingots in order to upgrade my
gear but i would much rather support
local businesses and support
my friends shops threads by scarra a
full netherright suit costs 64 diamonds
wow okay uh done do i just take it from
here i think i do supporting the local
economy you know i think that was scar's
first ever sale of netherrite armor so
i'm very happy to be able to give him
some diamonds because aqua town has been
a bit of a a project for scar and b-dubs
and they've created all kinds of shops
and i've made i've made it kind of a
priority to make sure that i'm buying
plenty from here i think over here this
was all me in fact i'm going to need a
lot more tnt very very soon and instead
of just farming it myself i think i
think it's time i gave my fellow hermits
a few diamonds for their efforts because
this is excellent and it's barely put a
dent in my finances so we should go to
another hermit shop to get all of our
stuff back you know someone pointed out
that
losing your stuff on a single-player
world is nothing like losing your stuff
on the hermitcraft server if you lose
your stuff on here cost you a few
diamonds but you can be up and running
again in no time at all if it's a single
player oh you're in for a rough ride
i've got all the books i need and now we
need to go and get some levels i'm back
to full power i've got my fresh gallmet
galytra gags and goots and i'm ready to
get myself back on the building spree
for the where is my b-dubs face where's
my beautiful boy my beautiful
baby boy who has done this we're gonna
we're not putting up with this we're
gonna put this straight back now
last episode you might remember that i
do you hear what's that mysterious
ticking noise is it just the town clock
that's not going to get annoying at all
so you might remember last episode i
blew up a couple of times now
if you have a problem you can bet your
bottom dollar that someone is gonna try
and fix it for you and that exactly
happened to me this ticking is gonna
drive me insane there we go turn that
down
and on reddit a user called the nefty
actually posted a design solution to my
problem which
i am very pleased to say genuinely works
i wasn't being trolled i didn't explode
and die no it genuinely worked and thank
you very much for submitting that design
from the little video that they posted i
was able to take exactly what i needed
from it to create this a brand new tnt
dispenser that is quite quite clever it
basically dispenses an observer which
then triggers all of these observers
here instantly so all of them will
dispense a t i mean it's beautifully
simple i'm very pleased to say that it
works only if you're at full health
let's give it a go
i'm not even scared because i know
we're going up
perfectly straight in
to my office how amazing is that
and you do take a bit of damage the only
problem is i don't actually have a
pretty easy way down uh
there's ticking i found the source of
the ticking clock but it looks like
there's
a lot more going on here well this looks
very loud so we've got ourselves a
really really cool
way up
the problem is we don't actually have
anything at the top
worth visiting so in today's episode i
want to get this place
kitted out for what i wanted first of
all we need to put baby boy b dubs his
face back up on the roof
i need something to look at
and what i'm also thinking what i'm
thinking is we link up these two areas
right here because i own both of these
buildings and i was thinking i could
make a little walkway between the two of
them and have an extra large very unique
office first let's get b dubs face back
all is right with the world
we've got a beautiful baby boy
back where he belongs i have i genuinely
have no idea where this face went i
don't i've looked around i haven't seen
it anywhere like it hasn't popped up
somewhere else on a building so
the mystery of the missing b-dubs face
is basically not solved i've just
replaced it but i've also done a little
bit of work and tidying up in my office
so here it is the complete thing i've
just i haven't really done a lot of
decorating down here but i have just
sort of tidied it up a little bit but
we're ready to go up are you at full
health
yes oh this is so clean i love it oh
sometimes
very occasionally
it just misses kind of i kind of baked
it up a little bit too much there didn't
i
scar's here to watch it fail
hello ah that scares me
no
hello
[Music]
i wasn't playing with my mandalorian
toys
do you wanna join and meet me in my
office
yeah but i don't wanna blow baby yoda up
you'll be fine
yeah you put no you need you need armor
you need armor
bail
[Laughter]
okay we're gonna go up ourselves now
hopefully
nice and clean and look at that it's
perfect and so i've done a little bit of
work inside here i now have an official
office i've got my like my little throny
chair there we've got creepy green
staring at the diamond chandelier i
managed to fit a mini diamond chandelier
in here and i think it looks pretty
awesome so that's that's pretty much it
this is my office i can see oh no didn't
manage to do that and i've also got like
a mr burns style trap door so if i'm
having a meeting with someone and i
don't like what they're saying i press
the button and down they go all the way
down i'm back i'm back dude i i was
talking
halfway here and i realized oh voice mod
did you not hear me saying you need
armor you need armor no
okay so the launcher is really really
clean and i absolutely love
the office maybe we should ask scar to
come and visit because i am absolutely
dying to try out my new mr burns
trapdoor
and also i've added a little walkway now
i did talk about this last episode i've
added a little walkway between the two
because i have two offices right i've
got both of these buildings and i kind
of wanted to connect the two so i have
done with a little bridge that's i think
this is kind of cute so i can travel
from one to the other so i haven't
decorated this particular one yet
because i actually think it's a bit of a
shame that there is a bunch of stone
here because i reckon
if i remove this i can
reveal
the really beautiful
big blue pyramidal pyramidal pip
pyramid
roof
that's part of this build so i think by
removing this i can add another diamond
chandelier here
and have i guess another office but i
think this stone is almost a little bit
of a shame and also this allows lots of
natural light in so we're going to
remove this there we go that is super
impressive and i think there's room here
for another diamond chandelier what are
you doing in my chair it clearly says
ceo of barge co
green my chair welcome to my office i
don't think so so check it out i have
built yet another diamond chandelier i
honestly i mean this i can't get enough
of these i think
just even remove the diamonds change the
diamonds to emeralds gold or iron i
think this design just really looks good
i i love it i reckon you could change
these to normal lanterns and i i don't i
don't have a seat i don't have a seat
okay i'll sit yes i don't think he's
thought this through i have called you
here because
of the head it needs to go this one with
fire no and get out of my office
i will not let you hurt my little baby
boy out out out
he just gave up immediately okay i don't
know what scar's got against this
beautiful b-dubs face but he's got a
real problem with it okay so yeah i've
got this lovely diamond chandelier and
i've kind of tried to decorate my office
to have as much space available around
it i've got myself a bed for when you
need to sleep on the job and i've got
myself a nice chair so i immediately
thought to myself why on earth have i
got two offices i've got one there with
a diamond chandelier and one here with a
diamond chandelier so i just thought to
myself okay well this is the assistant
to the ceo of marge co
and that's also
green that
bhajko is one man so in theory if i have
visitors
i need to stand here
either drop them through here or allow
them to see the ceo rush over here
and then take an appointment with them
you know what i might need some
employees i might need some additional
help at the barge there's a bit too much
going on and down here i plan on having
a bit of a workshop because i need to
practice some redstoney things but
between those clips i actually had to
take pretty much a full day
off of working on hermitcraft and the
reason was
that i actually had a special visitor
the make-a-wish charity got in touch
with me and said that there was a viewer
that really really wanted to meet me and
i offered to give them a tour of
hermitcraft so that's what i was doing
for pretty much most of the day and we
had a wonderful time walking around
seeing everything was built and we
actually made him a little house and i
promised that i would show it in a video
so here it is this is
barrybosses1234's house and we made it
on april fool's day of all days he's got
a skin that's very similar to mine i
wonder wonder where he got this skin
from and we made a lovely little
interior together and so his house here
and part of his make-a-wish is that he
is part of the green mansion so with
that detour out of the way i have shown
it as i promised we need to go back to
the barge because this is very much a
barge episode so if i go over here
that's where the barge is of course
i've got a little surprise here
and it is that there is no water i have
spent a couple of evenings this week
working on preparing my new
venture the next evolution of barge co
this is what i'm working on at the
moment and the premise is extremely
extremely simple i it's gonna take a lot
of building but the idea is simple it's
a mini game shopping experience and this
works best if i go and explain it
over in my workshop so
in this minigame you are in a minecart
the entire journey and there's powered
rails like this now along the track are
going to be multiple shulker boxes so
pretend that this is this is the build
that we're going through so the minecart
starts here
and as you go along you've got to grab
as much as you can from the shulker
boxes before you get too far away and
the gui closes so this might be going a
little bit faster than it is right now
but let's pretend that i'm going in i've
got to grab all the junk that i can and
if i get too far away it automatically
closes that is the concept it's going to
be a roller coaster ride where you pay
to enter and you can grab as much as you
physically can within an allotted time
and there's going to be music playing
and it's going to be amazing now what's
this called
well this is going to be called
the h c
b
s
of all things it's going to be called
the hc bbs
the hermitcraft big
barge sweep amazing i've been
conceptualizing and preparing for this
for a very very long time so where does
this start and how does it work is what
you're asking how do i join the hcbs
well
i'm planning and this is where i've run
into a bunch of problems with this
project already is that i wanted to
start at the barge hq i wanted it to
start here and i started digging a
tunnel all the way to where the barge
ends but i want it to play music which
means the jukebox will be out of range
so i've got a load of hurdles to
overcome with this before i can get it
even remotely ready for play testing
however i think i've got some ideas and
there's going to be some some very
tape and bubble gum ways of keeping this
together but basically that bit is going
to be like an introduction tutorial as
you get to here and then you're going to
press play on the real game and i've
also run into a bunch of issues such as
the vault down here and i was thinking
of actually just leaving this as it is
so what i need to do now i'm definitely
not going to be able to get this
finished in one episode because this is
an enormous task for a start i need to
finish mining out all the bits of this
roller coaster and then i'm gonna have
to build basically another barge and
then i'm gonna have to build a roller
coaster on that barge so this is this is
a multi-episode project right here but
i've i've revealed the plan so what i
think we should do is get into a proper
time lapse and get this thing
totally properly underway so that you
can see some real progress on this and
working out price and stuff i'm not sure
we'll work that out later on this could
be a disaster because if people pay 10
diamonds and they're able to take 50
diamonds worth of stuff
i messed up i will have messed up big
time so it's going to take a lot of play
testing and a lot of trial and error to
get this going but
hopefully that explains the premise
and let's get into a time lapse let's
go
[Music]
so i've got quite a lot of progress done
although it doesn't really look like it
all i've managed to do is this tunnel
but you'd be surprised how long this
sort of thing can take so i've been
preparing and planning what i would like
to do
so what i've got here is a
jukebox disc with my test on it now this
is just a rough example of what's going
to be like this is not the final disc
i just made something to kind of give it
a go so so you pay your 10 diamonds you
get here and then you're gonna play the
disc
welcome to the hc bbs the hermitcraft
big badge sweet that's me in this game
your task is extremely simple to open up
as many shulker boxes as humanly
possible and to get not that one there
that that one's empty you need to get as
many items from the shulker boxes as pos
can you can you hear
hello can you
so that's the idea you play the music
disc and it's going to talk to you and
play some music explain the rules of the
game during this
tunnel segment
then
when you eventually get to the end of
the tunnel segment that's when the game
really really begins you're going to go
on a roller coaster ride around a custom
made arena or barge map whatever you
want to call it and you've got to grab
as much stuff as possible but i got a
little bit stuck on some of the design
aspects of it so i know what i want to
do but i reckon what we need is as you
go around all of these we're on the
track it needs to be themed differently
so i'd like to see in the comments if
anyone has some ideas for what the
themes could be what could be going on
what could we have do we want like an
actual supermarket bit and then it could
transition into jurassic park or
whatever it is i'd like to hear some
ideas and then eventually you make your
way up
into this segment which is going to be a
very similar design to the barge also
this beacon flex was brought to you by
barge co i decided to make my beacon out
of diamond blocks because why not so
this project is going to keep me
extremely busy
for quite a few days and it's going to
take me a long time to actually get all
of the details right with all the
timings of the redstone and i'm going to
need some help probably from impulse or
someone who knows what they're doing i
can make this but i ca obviously i'm not
able to quite time everything just yet
so i just guessed for now but later on
down the line i'm gonna make this really
really seamless so i've done quite a lot
of work on this for now and i'm gonna
leave it where it is
for the rest of this episode because
there's one thing i really really want
to do before this episode ends and that
is the next edition
of the hermitcraft jungle map so
going back in time this is the first one
i ever did episode 25 in hindsight i
should have done one episode one or two
i kind of didn't think about it until
much later so this is what it looked
like while mumbo's base wasn't finished
look the mansion was barely started the
the back wasn't finished back then
and then i did another map set on
episode 41 and that was
about five months ago wait no wait
wow more like six or seven months ago so
a lot has changed scars base has
expanded look there's the old chest
monster i love the fact that that's on
the map ren's base has changed an
extreme amount
and a lot more progress has been done
although not an awful lot has changed on
the on the mansion but enough i think to
warrant the next stage
of the map
story so what we're going to do is set
up a space for this and we are going to
get all the maps now this takes over an
hour i know it doesn't look like a lot
but it genuinely takes an extremely long
time to get a map like this done so
we're gonna quickly
go ahead and sort this out
and be back in about two seconds for you
guys you know i never noticed but i
think if i stare at this i don't know if
it's just me or my eyes are playing
tricks on me but the the forest seems to
be sort of flashing like
slightly hi this is actually editing
green so i can see what you see and
there's definitely no flashing so
i think we can all agree that recording
green
is crazy
let's go back to the episode some
something weird with the lighting's
going on here anyway i have put together
a giant map and i've extended it an
entire line on the bottom because
ren's base ren's been going a bit mad
really hasn't he look at this he's he's
he's made an entire biome and i thought
it would be such a shame to miss out on
this hard work that he's been doing here
so i decided to expand it and get the
full effect so there's been some real
progress here the mansion looks a lot
cleaner still not finished around the
sides here but this main structure
definitely looks way cleaner than it did
and then scars base loads of progress
there ren's base he's put us all to
shame because he's got a whole bunch of
stuff that's popped up so i'm pretty
glad that i started this map thing
because at the end of the day it's
keeping a really nice record of how
things have progressed over time and
guess what there's still a small shulker
box
right here small shulker monster from
scar it's not over yet so i'm pretty
glad that i started that and we'll do
another one right at the end of the
season so i'm afraid that that is all i
have time for today it's been quite a
busy episode even if it didn't seem like
it and i have to say a huge thank you
for all the patience that you guys have
and for coming back even if i don't
upload for a week or two i've been
extremely busy in real life it happens i
am a real human being after all and i
have other things to do sometimes so
it's nice to know that i can take a few
days off just to get my house in order
and then come back and upload videos i
am hoping to be a bit more active but
there's uh still quite a lot that i need
to get sorted so
videos might be a little bit slower than
normal but it's amazing to have a
community that is quite happy to wait
those few extra days because i refuse to
put out a video that i'm not quite happy
with so
we're going to be working next on the hc
bbs for the next episode
so i'm going to go back to working on
that and i shall see you in the next
episode good bye